<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
    Document   : api-questions.xml
    Created on : November 4, 2002, 10:28 AM
    Author     : Jaroslav Tulach
    Description: Questions that should be answered in order to make better API
        
-->


<api-questions version="$Revision$" date="$date: $" >
    <category id="arch" name="General Informations">
        <question id="arch-what">
            What is this project good for?
            <hint>
            Please provide here few lines describing the the project, 
            what problem it should solve, provide links to documentation, 
            specifications, etc.
            </hint>
        </question>
        
    </category>
    <category id="dep" name="Project and platform dependencies">
        <question id="dep-nb">
            What other NetBeans projects this one depends on?
            <hint>
            If you want, describe such projects as imported API using
            the <code>&lt;api name="identification" type="import or export" category="stable" url="where is the description" /&gt;</code>
            </hint>
        </question>
        
        <question id="dep-non-nb">
            What other non-NetBeans projects this one depends on?
            
            <hint>
            Some non-NetBeans projects are packaged as NetBeans modules
            (see <a href="http://libs.netbeans.org">libraries</a>) and
            it is prefered to use this approach when more modules may
            depend on such third-party library.
            </hint>
        </question>
        
        <question id="dep-platform">
            On which platforms your module run? Any? Does it run in the same
            way?
            <hint>
            If your module is using JNI or deals with special differences of
            OSes like filesystems, etc. please describe here what they are.
            </hint>
        </question>
        
        <question id="dep-jre">
            Which version of JRE you need (1.2, 1.3, 1.4, etc.)?
            <hint>
            It is expected that if your module runs on 1.x that it will run 
            on 1.x+1 if no, state that please. Also describe here cases where
            you run different code on different versions of JRE and why.
            </hint>
        </question>

        <question id="dep-jrejdk">
            Do you require JDK or is JRE enough?
        </question>
                
    </category>

    <category id="deploy" name="Deployment">
        <question id="deploy-jar">
            Do you deploy just module JAR file(s) or some other files?
            <hint>
            If your module consist just from one module JAR file, just confirm that.
            If it uses more than one JAR, describe where there are located, how
            they refer to each other. 
            If it consist of module JAR(s) and other files, please describe
            what is their purpose, why other files are necessary. Please 
            make sure that installation/deinstallation leaves the system 
            in state as it was before installation.
            </hint>
        </question>
    
        <question id="deploy-nbm">
            Can you deploy NBM via AutoUpdate center?
            <hint>
            If not why?
            </hint>
        </question>
        
        <question id="deploy-shared">
            Do you need to be installed in shared location or only in user directory?
            <hint>
            Installation location shall not matter, if it does explain why.
            </hint>
        </question>
        
        
        <question id="deploy-packages">
            Are packages of your module made inaccessible by not declaring them
            public?
            
            <hint>
            NetBeans module system allows restriction of access rights to
            public classes of your module from other modules. This prevents
            unwanted dependencies of others on your code and should be used
            whenever possible (<a href="http://www.netbeans.org/download/apis/org/openide/doc-files/upgrade.html#3.4-public-packages">
            public packages
            </a>). 
            </hint>
        </question>
        
        
    </category>
    
    <category id="compat" name="Compatiblity with environment">
        <question id="compat-i18n">
            Is your module correctly internationalized?
            <hint>
            Correct internationalization means that it obeys instuctions 
            at <a href="http://www.netbeans.org/devhome/docs/i18n/index.html">
            NetBeans I18N pages</a>.
            </hint>
        </question>
        <question id="compat-standards">
            Does the module implements or defines any standards? Is the 
            implementation exact or it deviates somehow?
        </question>
        <question id="compat-version">
            Does your module properly coexists with earlier and future
            versions? Can you correctly read settings? Will future
            versions be able to read settings?
            
            <hint>
            Very helpful for reading settings is to store version number
            there, so future versions can decide whether how to read/convert
            the settings and older versions can ignore the new ones.
            </hint>
        </question>
    </category>
    
    <category id="resources" name="Access to resources">
        <question id="resources-file">
            Does your module use <code>java.io.File</code> directly?
            
            <hint>
            NetBeans provide a logical wrapper over plain files called 
            <code>org.openide.filesystems.FileObject</code> that
            provides uniform access to such resources and is the prefered
            way that should be used. But of course there can be situations when
            this is not suitable.
            </hint>
        </question>
        <question id="resources-layer">
            Does your module provide own layer? Does it create some files or
            folders on it? What it is trying to communicate by that and with which 
            component?
            
            <hint>
            NetBeans allows automatic and declarative installation of resources 
            by module layers. Module register files into appropriate places
            and other components use that information to perform their task
            (build menu, toolbar, window layout, list of templates, set of
            options, etc.). 
            </hint>
        </question>
        
        <question id="resources-read">
            Does your module read any resources from layers? For what purpose?
            
            <hint>
            As this is some kind of intermodule dependency, it is a kind of API.
            Please describe it and clasify according to 
            <a href="http://openide.netbeans.org/tutorial/api-design.html#categories">
            common stability categories</a>.
            </hint>
        </question>
        
        <question id="resources-mask">
            Does your module mask/hide/override any resource provided by another one in
            module layer? 
            
            <hint>
            If you mask a file provided by another module, you probably depend
            on that and do not want the other module to (for example) change
            the file's name. That module shall thus make that file available as an API
            of some stability category.
            </hint>
        </question>
    </category>

    
    <category id="lookup" name="Lookup of components">
        <question id="lookup-lookup">
            Does your module uses <code>org.openide.util.Lookup</code>
            to find any components to communicate to? Which ones?
            
            <hint>
            Please describe the interfaces you are searching for, where 
            are defined, whether you are searching for just one or more of them,
            if the order is important, etc. Also clasify the stability of such
            API contract.
            </hint>
        </question>
        <question id="lookup-register">
            Do you register anything into the lookup for other to find? 
            <hint>
            Do you register using layer file or using <code>META-INF/services</code>?
            Who is supposed to find your component?
            </hint>
        </question>
        <question id="lookup-remove">
            Are removing entries of other modules from the lookup? 
            <hint>
            Why? Of course, that is possible, but it can be dangerous. Is the module
            your are masking resource from aware of what you are doing?
            </hint>
        </question>
    </category>

    
    <!-- clasification of interfaces -->
    
    <!-- package names -->
    
    
    <category id="exec" name="Execution Environment">
        <question id="exec-property">
            Is execution of your code influenced by any environment of
            system (<code>System.getProperty</code>) property?
            
            <hint>
            If there is a property that can change the behaviour of your 
            code, somebody will likely use it. You should describe what it does 
            and the stability category of this API. You may use
            <PRE>
                &lt;property name="id" category="private" &gt
                    description of the property, where it is used, what it influence, etc.
                &lt;/property&gt;            
            </PRE>
            </hint>
        </question>
        
        <question id="exec-component">
            Is execution of your code influenced by (string) property
            of any of your components?
        </question>

        <question id="exec-classloader">
            Does your code uses own classloader?
        </question>
                
    </category>
    
    <category id="format" name="Format of files and protocols">
        <question id="format-types">
            Which file formats your code reads or writes on disk?
        </question>
        
        <question id="format-dnd">
            Which protocols your code understands during drag-n-drop?
        </question>
        
        <question id="format-clipboard">
            Which protocols your code reads/inserts when communicating with
            clipboard?
        </question>
        
    </category>

    
    <category id="performance" name="Performance and Scalability">
        <question id="perf-startup">
            Does your module executes anything on startup?
        </question>
        <question id="perf-exit">
            Does your module executes anything on exit?
        </question>
        <question id="perf-scale">
            Which external criteria influence the performance of your
            program (size of file in editor, number of files in menu, 
            in source directory, etc.) and how well your code scales?
            Please include some estimates.
        </question>
        <question id="perf-limit">
            Are there any limits in number/size of elements your code
            can handle?
        </question>
        <!-- multithreading -->
    
        <question id="perf-mem">
            What is the amount of memory your component occupies? Estimate
            with a relaction to the number of windows, etc.
        </question>
        
        <question id="perf-wakeup">
            Is any piece of your code waking up periodically?
        </question>

        <question id="perf-progress">
            Does your module executes some long running task?
            <hint>Typically they are tasks like connecting over
            network, computing huge amount of data, compilation.
            Such communication should be done asynchronously (for example
            using <code>RequestProcessor</code>), definitively it should 
            not block AWT thread.
            </hint>
        </question>

        <question id="perf-huge_dialogs">
            Does your module contain any dialogs or wizards with huge
            amount of GUI controls like combo boxes, lists, trees, text
            areas?
        </question>

        <question id="perf-menus">
            Does your module use dynamically changing context menus or
            context sensitive actions with complicated logic for enable/disable?
        </question>
        
    </category>
    
    
    <!-- security -->
    <!-- recovery -->
    
</api-questions>
