<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<application xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	     xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
	     xsi:schemaLocation="http://research.sun.com/wadl/2006/10 
                    ../../../../../../../../../../websvc.saas.api/src/org/netbeans/modules/websvc/saas/model/wadl20061109.xsd"
	     xmlns="http://research.sun.com/wadl/2006/10">
    <grammars/>    
    <resources base="http://www.zvents.com/rest">
        <resource path="search">
            <method name="GET" id="zvents.searchGet">
                <doc xml:lang="en">
                    Search for events based on the type indicated in the &quot;what&quot; parameter.
                    API documentation :  http://corporate.zvents.com/developers/documentation/search.html  
                </doc>
                <request>
                    <param name="key" type="xsd:string" required="true" style="query">
                    </param>
                    <param name="what" type="xsd:string" required="false" style="query">
                        <doc xml:lang="en">
                            A string indicating the type of event, such as &quot;parade&quot;
                            or &quot;dancing&quot;.
                        </doc>
                    </param>
                    <param name="where" type="xsd:string" required="false" style="query">
                        <doc xml:lang="en">
                            A string describing a location around which the search results will be 
                            restricted. (e.g., san francisco, ca or 94131). You can also specify a 
                            location using a longitude/latitude coordinate pair using the notation -74.0:BY:40.9
                        </doc>
                    </param>
                    <param name="when" type="xsd:string" required="false" style="query">
                        <doc xml:lang="en">
                            A string specifying a date range for the search (e.g., today, this week, next week, 
                            friday, etc.). Explicit date ranges can be specified by separating two dates with the word 
                            "to" (e.g., monday to thursday, 10/30/2007 to 11/4/2007). Leave this string blank to search all future events.
                        </doc>
                    </param>
                    <param name="radius" type="xsd:string" required="false" style="query">
                        <doc xml:lang="en">
                            The number of miles around the location (specified in the where field) to search. 
                            If this field is left blank, a default radius is supplied. The default raidus varies 
                            according to the location specified in the where field.
                        </doc>
                    </param>
                    <param name="limit" type="xsd:string" required="false" style="query">
                        <doc xml:lang="en">
                            The maximum number of matching events to return. The default is 10 and maximum is 25.
                        </doc>
                    </param>
                    <param name="offset" type="xsd:string" required="false" style="query">
                        <doc xml:lang="en">
                            The number of events to skip from the beginning of the search results. 
                            If a search matches 1000 events, returning 25 events starting at offset 100 will
                            return event numbers 100-125 that match the search..
                        </doc>
                    </param>
                    <param name="trim" type="xsd:string" required="false" style="query">
                        <doc xml:lang="en">
                            Set to 1 if repeating events should be trimmed from the search results. 
                            Set to 0 to return repeating events. If the trim option is enabled, only 1 
                            event will be returned from each repeating series that matches the search. 
                            The number of events within the series that match the search is returned in the
                            series_count response parameter. Defaults to 1.
                        </doc>
                    </param>
                    <param name="sort" type="xsd:string" required="false" style="query">
                        <doc xml:lang="en">
                           Set to 1 to sort search results by time. Set to 0 to sort search results by relevance. Defaults to 0.
                        </doc>
                    </param>
                    <param name="cat" type="xsd:string" required="false" style="query">
                        <doc xml:lang="en">
                            Restrict your search to items that belong to a specific category. 
                            You must provide a category identifier which can be determined using the categories API call.
                        </doc>
                    </param>
                    <param name="catex" type="xsd:string" required="false" style="query">
                        <doc xml:lang="en">
                            Exclude items from a specific category from the search. 
                            You must provide a category identifier which can be determined using the categories API call.
                        </doc>
                    </param>
                    <param name="cc" type="xsd:string" required="false" style="query">
                        <doc xml:lang="en">
                            Set to 1 to include category information in the search results. This will 
                            give you the list of categories within the search result set. You can search 
                            within a specific category using the cat option. Defaults to 0.
                        </doc>
                    </param>
                    <param name="rec" type="xsd:string" required="false" style="query">
                        <doc xml:lang="en">
                           Set to 1 to include a list of events within the same repeat series that 
                           occur within the time range of the search. Defaults to 0.
                        </doc>
                    </param>		
                </request>
                <response>
                </response>
            </method>
        </resource>
    </resources>

</application>